hi my name is Joe brewer and I want to
create a new field of science that
integrates all the knowledge and the
cognitive and behavioral sciences and
uses it to create rigorous methodologies
for addressing global change in the 21st
century specifically I want to study how
we collectively respond to what I call
systemic risk by a systemic risk I mean
that there are problems that arise in
one area that affect one system that
then propagate into other areas in other
systems and can have a cascade effect of
damage and harm a recent example as the
earthquake that took place off of the
coast of Japan in early 2011 that caused
the creation of a tsunami that tsunami
flooded the lowland areas of Japan it
spread to where there were nuclear
reactors went over their walls flooded
the reactors caused a meltdown of the
core of those reactors which then caused
a huge explosion a release of
radioactive material into the atmosphere
that's contaminated the region and to
some extent various parts of the world
so have these problems where there are
different systems that are all
interconnected with each other and the
risks flow from one system to another
and often unexpected ways ways that we
didn't anticipate when we designed those
systems and what I found in the last
several years is that there's a
particular piece of this problem that's
really essential to get right if we're
going to solve it and that piece is
human beings embeddedness into the
system how do people think about and
understand the systems that are embedded
in what are the tools and procedures
protocols that they use to engage with
these different systems say when there's
a disaster what are the emergency
response protocols
how does disaster relief get done how
does medical care get provided to people
on the ground all the ways that human
beings respond and
to these big challenges when I found is
that there are a lot of assumptions out
there about human beings they're often
based on what I call a priori philosophy
which means assumptions that are coming
about beforehand before thinking through
how people actually work but what's been
happening is this there was a silent
revolution in academia where in the
cognitive and behavioral sciences a new
view of human nature is emerging that's
scientifically rigorous and cures
empirically sound testable and extremely
useful for answering questions about how
human beings connect up or interface
with global systems so unfortunately all
the knowledge and cognitive science like
so many fields of knowledge in academia
and in the world
they're siloed from each other and two
disciplines like psychology and even
more narrowly personality research or
cognitive neuroscience or other areas
like linguistics in the study of
language across cultures and so what
I've what I found in my study of
cognitive science is that too many
researchers and practitioners are stuck
within those categories as boxes they
don't know about the findings and the
tools that are coming out of other areas
and increasingly the problems that they
have to address require higher levels of
synthesis and integration of knowledge
in order for them to be solved so what
I'm proposing to do is to enter a ph.d
program preferably at a university that
has a wide array of very
forward-thinking research centers and
what I want to do is to map out the
knowledge the methodologies that exist
in the cognitive and behavioral sciences
that can be packaged together to create
more robust tools for analysis as well
as implementation tools for actually
going in and changing systems designing
them so that the human interface works
better so that we can respond to
systemic threats now one example to
really get you thinking more clearly
about this there
an area of research in cognitive
psychology that looks at what's called
metacognition in group process which is
basically looking at tools that are used
by people in a group that help them to
work together as a group to have a
collective intelligence a really simple
example is a visualization tool so there
might be that there's a flow chart that
shows everyone what the project is what
problem they're solving what all the
vital pieces are the timeline that needs
to be used to solve them and what each
person's part is the tasks and
responsibilities to go through that flow
chart and help contribute to solving a
more complex task so that would be an
example of a form of metacognition a way
of thinking embedded outside of the
individual and in the group that's used
to help them see the complexity and to
see their place and addressing the
complexity effectively and fulfilling
their role so what I want to do is
create an an inventory if you will or a
map a taxonomy of all the different
tools and theories the methodologies
that exist in the cognitive and
behavioral sciences that could be used
for disaster relief for designing change
in urban landscapes to help us
transition away from fossil fuels and
other big challenges and I want to apply
this knowledge in collaboration with
people who are on the ground trying to
implement these solutions now right now
I feel like there's a desperate need for
this I feel like it doesn't really exist
anywhere and it's something that I've
been working on for a number of years
and I know that I can't finish it
without going back into academia
pursuing a PhD in partnering with
leading researchers and scholars in a
very vast array of fields to accomplish
the goal so that's why I've been
thinking about pursuing a PhD and that's
what I hope to accomplish is to create a
new science if you will of human
interface methodologies for addressing
global challenges and I'd love your help
to get there so if you have ideas of
people who have tools and insights whose
work could be useful please share them
with me if you know of academic programs
that could help me to do this I actually
have one in mind my number
choices to go to the Oxford and the UK
and work at their Martin school for 21st
century challenges but maybe you know of
other places that could be useful as
well and if you know if people who would
like to see this work done I'd really
like to talk to them so please put them
in touch with me I'll include my contact
information witnessed post and I'd love
to talk more with anyone and everyone
who would like to help make this dream
into a reality thank you